wahanda.com 2012-06-25

# Privacy and Cookie Policy - Wahanda

### Introduction

The Wahanda website is owned and operated by Hotspring Ventures Limited (“ **we** ”, “ **our** ” or “ **us** ”). We are committed to protecting the privacy of our users and customers. This privacy policy (“ **Privacy Policy** ”) is intended to inform you how we gather, define, and use your personal information, such as your name, email address, address and other contact details (“ **Personal Information** ”). Please use this Privacy Policy to help you decide whether and how you wish to use our site and our products and services. Please take a moment to read it carefully.

All your Personal Information shall be used in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 (the ' **Act** '). If you want to know what information we collect and hold about you, please write to us at:

Hotspring Ventures Limited, 1 Regent Street (c/o Calder & Co), London SW1Y 4NW.

Alternatively email us on [hello@wahanda.com](mailto:hello@wahanda.com) or call us on 0203 384 5358

Hotspring Ventures Limited is the data controller of your Personal Information for the purpose of the Act.

### What information do we collect?

When you visit our website we may collect the following information:

  * Personal information that you choose to share with us when you register for services, emails, newsletters and alerts.
  * If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses.
  * Information about the way our website has been used by you and others – collected on an aggregate basis.
  * Your IP address and other information (such as the browser you are using) may be collected when you interact with our website – for example create a profile, subscribe to our emails, ask or answer a question etc. We may associate this information with your Wahanda account.

It is important that all the Personal Information you give us when you register as a member or otherwise when you use the website is correct and accurate. This includes, by way of example only, ensuring that we have your correct contact (including e-mail) details at all times.

We strive to maintain the highest standards of security, however the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. So, whilst we will do our best to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our website. Any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your Personal Information we will use strict procedures and security features to prevent unauthorized access.

### How do we use the information you provide to us?

In general terms, we use Personal Information for the purpose of administering and expanding our business activities, providing customer service and making other products and services available to our customers and prospective customers. Occasionally, we may also use the Personal Information we collect to notify you about important changes to our website, and new services and special offers we think you will find valuable. Please note that this will only be done if you have consented to receiving such communications at the point of registration. You may notify us at any time if you do not wish to receive these communications by emailing us at [hello@wahanda.com](mailto:hello@wahanda.com).

### Opt out of receiving emails

You can unsubscribe from our regular emails at any time by clicking on the Unsubscribe link in the footer of the email you have received. Alternatively, you may email us at [hello@wahanda.com](mailto:hello@wahanda.com). Please allow 48 hours for your email address to be removed from our system.

### Our policy on Cookies

In common with other commercial websites, our website utilises a standard technology called “cookies” (see explanation below, “What Is A Cookie?”) and web server logs to collect information about how our website is used. Information gathered through cookies and web server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our website, and the websites visited just before and just after our website.

We use cookies to: 
  * remember you when you visit this website to keep track of your browsing patterns and to build up a profile of how you and other users use the website.
  * make our website work as efficiently as possible.
  * facilitate transactions and administer services to you and to our partners.

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a very small text document, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier. When you visit a website, that site's computer asks your computer for permission to store this file in a part of your hard drive specifically designated for cookies. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but in order to protect your privacy, your browser only permits a website to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites. Find out more about the use of cookies on [www.cookiecentral.com](http://www.cookiecentral.com/)

### How do we use information we collect from cookies?

As you browse our site, the site uses its cookies to differentiate you from other users to prevent you from seeing unnecessary advertisements or requiring you to log in more often than is necessary. Cookies, in conjunction with our web server's log files, allow us to calculate the aggregate number of people visiting our website and to determine which parts of the site are most popular. This helps us gather feedback to constantly improve our website and better serve our customers.

Cookies do not allow us to gather any personal information about you and we do not generally store any personal information that you provided to us in your cookies.

### Third Party Cookies

Most of the cookies we use are ours, however, on occasion, we will issue a cookie by a third party to help us operate the site -- these are sometimes known as “web beacons” or “clear gifts”. These cookies cannot be used to identify an individual; they can only be used for statistical purposes, for example, in providing you with advertisements that are more relevant to your interests.

For example, third party vendors such as Google, show our ads on sites on the internet and use cookies, to serve ads based on your prior visits to our website and to determine which advertisements and promotions users have seen and how users responded to them and to serve advertising to our website. Analytics data may also be used to this effect.

For this purpose, we may disclose generic, aggregated or anonymised data relating to your visits and use of our website, but _we will not disclose any of your Personal Information which identifies you or from which you may be identifiable_ i.e. we will not disclose your contact details such as your email address, name, address or telephone number.

The third party companies that generate these cookies have their own, very strict, privacy policies but we don't have access to these cookies; other than allowing them to be served, we have no role to play in these cookies at all (although we may use statistical information arising from these third party cookies and provided to us by third parties, to improve our website experience).

You may opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page](http://www.google.com/privacy/ads/). For more information on opting out of third party vendors' use of cookies please visit the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) website.

### How do I remove or block cookies?

Most browsers allow you to remove any cookies and/or block any new cookies being set. To turn off cookies, look at the “help” menu on your browser. However, please note, that switching off cookies may restrict your use of the website and/or delay or affect the way in which it operates.

### Sharing personal information with third parties

We treat the security and method of processing your Personal Information very seriously, and we will never sell your personal information under any circumstances. 

However, we may disclose your Personal Information to selected third parties in the following situations:

  * to facilitate our business, including, by way of example only, sending email communications; 
  * if we buy or sell any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your Personal Information to the seller or buyer of such business or assets, as appropriate;
  * if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data to comply with any legal obligation or in order to enforce or apply our terms and conditions and other agreements or protect the rights, property, or safety of our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

We may also disclose your Personal Information to third parties in accordance with your authorization as expressed via ‘opt-ins’ e.g. at the point of registration.

Please note: by posting any personal information in any publicly accessible area of our website, such information may be collected by third parties over which we have no control. We strongly recommend all users keep postings anonymous. We are not responsible for the use of such information by such third parties.

Please therefore exercise all due care and consideration before disclosing any personal Information that will be disclosed on public areas. You should also avoid disclosing any personal Information that may be used to identify you (such as your name, age, home or work address or name of your employer) especially if you disclose any sensitive personal Information such as:

  * racial or ethnic origin; 
  * political beliefs; 
  * philosophical or religious beliefs; 
  * membership of a trade union or political party; 
  * physical or mental health; 
  * sexual life; or 
  * the commission of criminal offences or proceedings. 

### How can you access and correct your personal information?

Should you have any queries about any Personal Information which we hold about you, you may submit a request to us by sending an email to [hello@wahanda.com](mailto:hello@whanda.com) and we shall endeavor to respond to any such request as soon as we are able. We may charge you an administration charge of £10 for fulfilling any such request.

### What about other websites linked to our website?

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our website nor the information or content contained therein. Often links to other websites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to the users of our website.

Please remember that when you use a link to go from our website to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link on our website, is subject to that website's own rules and policies. Always read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

### Your consent

By using our website you consent to our collection and use of your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our website homepage to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. By continuing to access our website after any change is posted, you agree to any such change to our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with such changes, you should stop using our website.

### Where we store your personal data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to and stored at a destination outside the European Economic Area. By submitting your Personal Information you agree to this transfer. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your Personal Information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Partners

If you place an order or otherwise engage with Wahanda through a third party white label solution (including but not limited to: http://metro.wahanda.com or http://eveningstandard.wahanda.com), then your email address and contact details will be passed on to the relevant partner.

_This Policy was last updated on May 28, 2012._
